The Americans came to Beijing to do
business, and this was visible at every
stage of the visit, beginning with the
composition of the US delegation itself.
Although formally the delegation was of
course led by President Trump, on the
diplomatic level the visit was
coordinated by Treasury Secretary Scott
Bessent, rather than as had usually been
the case in the past, by Secretary of
State Marco Rubio.
And that was hardly surprising. Trump
did not come to Beijing to divide the
world with China into new spheres of
influence.
He came hoping that the Chinese would
sign deals for Boeing aircraft, for beef
and soybeans from American farmers, and
for Nvidia chips.